<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrfdoc xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
    <DocumentTitle>Apache log4j2 log messages substitution (CVE-2021-44228)</DocumentTitle>
    <DocumentType>Fortinet PSIRT Advisories</DocumentType>
    <DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
        <ContactDetails>
            Fortinet PSIRT Contact:
            Email: vulnwatch@fortinet.com
            Website: fortiguard.com/psirt-pgpkey
        </ContactDetails>
     </DocumentPublisher>
    <DocumentTracking>
        
        <Identification>
            <ID>FG-IR-21-245</ID>
        </Identification>
        

        

        <CurrentReleaseDate>2021-12-12T00:00:00</CurrentReleaseDate>
    </DocumentTracking>
    <DocumentNotes>
        
        <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary">
            Apache Log4j See the Fortinet Blog for more more detail https://www.fortinet.com/blog/psirt-blogs/apache-log4j-vulnerability
        </Note>
        

        

        
        <Note Title="Impact" Type="Description">
            Execute unauthorized code or commands
        </Note>
        

        
        <Note Title="Affected Products" Type="Description">
            The following products are NOT impacted: FortiADC FortiAI FortiAnalyzer FortiAP FortiAP-U FortiAuthenticator FotiCache FortiCarrier FortiClient (All versions) FortiClientEMS FortiConnect FortiConverter FortiDDoS FortiDDoS-F FortiDeceptor FortiEDR Agent FortiExtender FortiMail FortiManager FortiNAC FortiOS (includes FortiGate &amp; FortiWiFi) FortiPresence FortiProxy FortiRecorder (inlcudes FortiCamera) FortiSandbox FortiSASE FortiSOAR FortiSwitch &amp; FortiSwitchManager FortiTester FortiToken &amp; FortiToken Mobile FortiVoice (includes FortiPhone) FortiWeb FortiWLC FortiWLM FortiAnalyzer Cloud FortiClient Cloud FortiExtender Cloud FortiGate Cloud FortiGSLB Cloud FortiLAN Cloud (includes Switch &amp; AP) FortiManager Cloud FortiPenTest FortiPhish Cloud FortiToken Cloud FortiWeb Cloud The following products are impacted and fixes are being worked on. This advisory will be updated as soon as ETAa are available: FortiAIOps - Fixed in version 1.0.2 FortiAnalyzer BigData - Fixed on 2021-12-10 in 6.4.7 &amp; 7.0.2 FortiCASB - Fixed on 2021-12-10 FortiConverter Portal - Fixed on 2021-12-10 FortiCWP - Fixed on 2021-12-10 FortiEDR Cloud - Not exploitable. Additional precautionary mitigations put in place on 2021-12-10 FortiInsight - Not exploitable. Additional precautionary mitigations being investigated. FortiIsolator - Fix scheduled for version 2.3.4 FortiMonitor - Mitigations for NCM &amp; Elastiflow available FortiPortal - Fixed in 6.0.8 and 5.3.8 FortiSIEM - Mitigation available ShieldX - Fix scheduled for versions 2.1 and 3.0 - ETA 2021/12/17 Update: CVE-2021-45046 (CVSS score: 3.9 - Low)It was found by the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) that the fix they released to address CVE-2021-44228 in Apache Log4j 2.15.0 was incomplete in certain non-default configurations. This could allow attackers with control over Thread Context Map (MDC) input data when the logging configuration uses a non-default Pattern Layout, with either a Context Lookup or a Thread Context Map pattern, to craft malicious input data using a JNDI Lookup pattern resulting in a denial of service (DOS) attack Products marked NOT impacted remain so. Additionally the following products are not impacted, or the previous fix includes a fix for CVE-2021-45046: FortiAIOps FortiConvertor Portal FortiEDR Cloud FortiPortal
        </Note>
        

        
        <Note Title="Solutions" Type="Description">
            For full details of protections and detections for the IoCs related to this vulnerability, please see the Log4j2 Vulnerability Outbreak Alert (https://www.fortiguard.com/outbreak-alert/log4j2-vulnerability) IPS Signature protection (FortiOS) Fortinet have released&amp; IPS signature Apache.Log4j.Error.Log.Remote.Code.Execution, with VID 51006 to address this threat. This signature was initially released in IPS package (version 19.215),. Please note that, since this is an emergency release, the default action for this signature is set to pass. Please modify the action according to your need. As of IPS DB version 19.217 this signature was set to drop by default. IPS Signature protection (FortiADC &amp; FortiProxy) FortiADC supports IPS signature to mitigate log4j (version 19.215).FortiProxy supports IPS signature to mitigate log4j (version 19.215). Web Application Firewall (FortiWeb &amp; FortiWeb Cloud) Web Application signatures to prevent this vulnerability were first added in database 0.00305 and have been updated in recent releases to add additional coverage Using FortiAnalyzer to detect activities related to exploits of Apache Log4j2 vulnerability Last Updated: Tuesday December 15, 8:50 PM Pacific Time
        </Note>
        

        

    </DocumentNotes>

    
    <DocumentReferences>
        
        <Reference>
            <URL>&lt;a href=&#34;https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/security.html&#34;&gt;https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/security.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;</URL>
            <Description>&lt;a href=&#34;https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/security.html&#34;&gt;https://logging.apache.org/log4j/2.x/security.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br&gt;</Description >
        </Reference>
        
        <Reference>
            <URL>&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fortinet.com/blog/psirt-blogs/apache-log4j-vulnerability&#34;&gt;https://www.fortinet.com/blog/psirt-blogs/apache-log4j-vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;</URL>
            <Description>&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fortinet.com/blog/psirt-blogs/apache-log4j-vulnerability&#34;&gt;https://www.fortinet.com/blog/psirt-blogs/apache-log4j-vulnerability&lt;/a&gt;</Description >
        </Reference>
        
    </DocumentReferences>
    

    

    
    
    
        
            <Vulnerability xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
                <CVE>CVE-2021-44228</CVE>
            </Vulnerability>
        
    

    
</cvrfdoc>