<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.1</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-01-20T16:14:30</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.1</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-02T22:17:18</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated Fixed Releases.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-01-20T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-02-02T22:17:18</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Multiple vulnerabilities in Cisco SD-WAN products could allow an authenticated attacker to perform command injection attacks against an affected device, which could allow the attacker to take certain actions with root privileges on the device.

For more information about these vulnerabilities, see the Details ["#details"] section of this advisory.

Cisco has released software updates that address these vulnerabilities. There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">These vulnerabilities affect the following Cisco products if they are running a vulnerable release of Cisco SD-WAN Software:

SD-WAN vBond Orchestrator Software
SD-WAN vEdge Cloud Routers
SD-WAN vEdge Routers
SD-WAN vManage Software
SD-WAN vSmart Controller Software

For information about which Cisco software releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by these vulnerabilities.

Cisco has confirmed that these vulnerabilities do not affect Cisco IOS XE SD-WAN Software.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">The vulnerabilities are not dependent on one another; exploitation of one of the vulnerabilities is not required to exploit another vulnerability. In addition, a software release that is affected by one of the vulnerabilities may not be affected by the other vulnerabilities.

Details about the vulnerabilities are as follows:

CVE-2021-1299: Cisco SD-WAN vManage Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the web-based management interface of Cisco SD-WAN vManage Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to execute arbitrary commands as the root user on an affected system.

This vulnerability is due to improper input validation of user-supplied input to the device template configuration. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by submitting crafted input to the device template configuration. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to gain root-level access to the affected system.

This vulnerability affects only the Cisco SD-WAN vManage product.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvu28387 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvu28387"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1299
Security Impact Rating (SIR): Critical
CVSS Base Score: 9.9
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:C/C:H/I:H/A:H

CVE-2021-1261: Cisco SD-WAN CLI Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the CLI utility tcpdump of Cisco SD-WAN Software could allow an authenticated, local attacker with read-only credentials to inject arbitrary commands that could allow the attacker to obtain root privileges.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of user-supplied input to the tcpdump command. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by authenticating with a lower-privileged user account via the CLI of an affected device and submitting crafted input to the affected commands. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary commands on the device with root privileges.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvi59639 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvi59639"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1261
Security Impact Rating (SIR): High
CVSS Base Score: 7.8
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:H

CVE-2021-1260: Cisco SD-WAN CLI Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the CLI of Cisco SD-WAN Software could allow an authenticated, local attacker with read-only credentials to inject arbitrary commands that could allow the attacker to obtain root privileges and read, write, and delete files of the underlying file system of an affected device.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of user-supplied input on the CLI. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by authenticating with read-only privileges via the CLI of an affected device and submitting crafted input to the affected commands. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary commands on the device with root privileges.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvi59635 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvi59635"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1260
Security Impact Rating (SIR): High
CVSS Base Score: 7.1
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:N

CVE-2021-1263: Cisco SD-WAN CLI Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the CLI of Cisco SD-WAN Software could allow an authenticated, local attacker with read-only credentials to inject arbitrary commands that could allow the attacker to obtain root privileges and read, write, and delete files of the underlying file system of an affected device.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of user-supplied input on the CLI. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by authenticating with read-only privileges via the CLI of an affected device and submitting crafted input to the affected commands. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary commands on the device with root privileges.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvu28443 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvu28443"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1263
Security Impact Rating (SIR): Medium
CVSS Base Score: 6.1
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:L/A:N

CVE-2021-1262: Cisco SD-WAN CLI Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the CLI of Cisco SD-WAN Software could allow an authenticated, local attacker with read-only credentials to inject arbitrary commands that could allow the attacker to obtain root privileges and read files from the underlying file system of an affected device.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of user-supplied input on the CLI. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by authenticating with read-only privileges via the CLI of an affected device and submitting crafted input to the affected commands. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary commands on the device with root privileges.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvi69982 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvi69982"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1262
Security Impact Rating (SIR): Medium
CVSS Base Score: 5.5
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:N/A:N

CVE-2021-1298: Cisco SD-WAN vManage Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the vAnalytics feature of the web-based management interface of Cisco SD-WAN vManage Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to execute arbitrary commands as the root user on an affected system.

This vulnerability is due to improper input validation of user-supplied input to the SSO configuration. An attacker could exploit this by submitting crafted input to the SSO configuration. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to gain root-level access to the system.

The vAnalytics feature of Cisco SD-WAN vManage Software must be enabled for this vulnerability to be exploited.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvm26011 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvm26011"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1298
Security Impact Rating (SIR): Medium
CVSS Base Score: 5.3
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:H/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:N/I:H/A:N</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerabilities described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
      Fixed Releases
Customers are advised to upgrade to an appropriate fixed software release as indicated in the following table(s). To ensure a complete upgrade solution, consider that this advisory is part of a collection that includes the following advisories:

cisco-sa-sdwan-abyp-TnGFHrS ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-abyp-TnGFHrS"]: Cisco SD-WAN vManage Authorization Bypass Vulnerabilities
cisco-sa-sdwan-bufovulns-B5NrSHbj ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-bufovulns-B5NrSHbj"]: Cisco SD-WAN Buffer Overflow Vulnerabilities
cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn"]: Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities
cisco-sa-sdwan-dosmulti-48jJuEUP ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-dosmulti-48jJuEUP"]: Cisco SD-WAN Denial of Service Vulnerabilities

         Cisco SD-WAN Release  First Fixed Release for These Vulnerabilities  First Fixed Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories          Earlier than 18.3  Migrate to a fixed release.  Migrate to a fixed release.      18.3  Migrate to a fixed release.  Migrate to a fixed release.      18.4  Migrate to a fixed release.  Migrate to a fixed release.      19.2  19.2.4  Migrate to a fixed release.      19.3  Migrate to a fixed release.  Migrate to a fixed release.      20.1  20.1.2  Migrate to a fixed release.      20.3  20.3.2  20.3.2      20.4  20.4.1  20.4.1</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerabilities that are described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">The following vulnerabilities were found during the resolution of a Cisco TAC support case: CVE-2021-1260 and CVE-2021-1261.

The following vulnerabilities were found during internal security testing:

James Spadaro of Cisco: CVE-2021-1262
Joseph Connor of Cisco: CVE-2021-1263
Andrew Kim of Cisco: CVE-2021-1298
Alex Lumsden of Cisco: CVE-2021-1299</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco SD-WAN Solution" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-238692">Cisco SD-WAN Solution </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco SD-WAN vManage" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-271450">Cisco SD-WAN vManage </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco SD-WAN vEdge router" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278041">Cisco SD-WAN vEdge router </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco SD-WAN vEdge Cloud" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278078">Cisco SD-WAN vEdge Cloud </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco SD-WAN vContainer" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278124">Cisco SD-WAN vContainer </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1263</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvu28443</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvu28443</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1263</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-271450</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278078</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278041</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-238692</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278124</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>6.1</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:L/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="2" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1260</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvi59635</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvi59635</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1260</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278124</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278078</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-271450</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-238692</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278041</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>8.1</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="3" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1298</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvm26011</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvm26011</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1298</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278078</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-238692</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278124</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-271450</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278041</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>5.3</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:H/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:N/I:H/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="4" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1262</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvi69982</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvi69982</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1262</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278124</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278078</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-238692</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278041</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-271450</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>5.5</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:N/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="5" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1261</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvi59639</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvi59639</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1261</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278078</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-238692</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278041</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278124</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-271450</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.8</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="6" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1299</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvu28387</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvu28387</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1299</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-271450</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>9.9</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:C/C:H/I:H/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sdwan-cmdinjm-9QMSmgcn</URL>
        <Description>Cisco SD-WAN Command Injection Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>