<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance Vulnerabilities</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-ucsi2-dtcinj-yH5U4RSx</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.0</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-07-21T15:40:12</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-07-21T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-07-21T16:00:00</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Multiple vulnerabilities in the web-based management interface of Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to conduct a path traversal or command injection attack on an affected system.

These vulnerabilities are due to insufficient input validation. An attacker could exploit these vulnerabilities by using the web-based management interface to do one or both of the following:

Execute a command using crafted input
Upload a file that has been altered using path traversal techniques

A successful exploit could allow the attacker to read and write arbitrary files or execute arbitrary commands as root on an affected system.

For more information about these vulnerabilities, see the Details ["#details"] section of this advisory.

Cisco has released software updates that address these vulnerabilities. There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-ucsi2-dtcinj-yH5U4RSx ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-ucsi2-dtcinj-yH5U4RSx"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">At the time of publication, these vulnerabilities affected Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance releases earlier than Release 1.0.9-292.

Note: These vulnerabilities do not affect customers who use Cisco Intersight Services for Cloud.

To determine the release of Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance, click the gear icon in the top right corner of the web UI, and then choose Settings &gt; Software. The web UI will display the release number.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="3">The vulnerabilities are not dependent on one another. Exploitation of one of the vulnerabilities is not required to exploit the other vulnerability. In addition, a software release that is affected by one of the vulnerabilities may not be affected by the other vulnerability.

Details about the vulnerabilities are as follows:

CVE-2021-1617: Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance Path Traversal Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the web-based management interface of Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to conduct a path traversal attack on an affected system.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient input validation. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by using the web-based management interface to do one or both of the following:

Execute a command using crafted input
Upload a file that has been altered using path traversal techniques

A successful exploit could allow the attacker to read and write arbitrary files on an affected system.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvy29621 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvy29621"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1617
Security Impact Rating (SIR): Medium
CVSS Base Score: 6.5
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:H/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:N

CVE-2021-1618: Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance Command Injection Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the web-based management interface of Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to conduct a command injection attack on an affected system.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient input validation. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by using the web-based management interface to execute a command using crafted input. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary commands as root on an affected system.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvy29622 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvy29622"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1618
Security Impact Rating (SIR): Medium
CVSS Base Score: 6.5
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:H/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:N</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
      Fixed Releases
At the time of publication, Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance releases 1.0.9-292 and later contained the fix for these vulnerabilities.

See the Details section in the bug ID(s) at the top of this advisory for the most complete and current information.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerabilities that are described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">These vulnerabilities were found during internal security testing by the Cisco Advanced Security Initiatives Group (ASIG).</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-ucsi2-dtcinj-yH5U4RSx</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance Vulnerabilities</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-283822">Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1617</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvy29621</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvy29621</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1617</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-283822</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>6.5</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:H/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-ucsi2-dtcinj-yH5U4RSx</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="2" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1618</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvy29622</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvy29622</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1618</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-283822</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>6.5</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:H/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-ucsi2-dtcinj-yH5U4RSx</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Intersight Virtual Appliance Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>