<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco Firepower 9000 Series Firepower 2-Port 100G Double-Width Network Module Queue Wedge Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-20190220-firpwr-dos</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.0</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2019-02-20T15:15:55</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2019-02-20T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2019-02-20T15:15:55</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in field-programmable gate array (FPGA) ingress buffer management for the Cisco Firepower 9000 Series with the Cisco Firepower 2-port 100G double-width network module (PID: FPR9K-DNM-2X100G) could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS) condition. Manual intervention may be required before a device will resume normal operations.

The vulnerability is due to a logic error in the FPGA related to the processing of different types of input packets. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by being on the adjacent subnet and sending a crafted sequence of input packets to a specific interface on an affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause a queue wedge condition on the interface. When a wedge occurs, the affected device will stop processing any additional packets that are received on the wedged interface.

There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190220-firpwr-dos ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190220-firpwr-dos"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability is specific to the Cisco Firepower 9000 Series with the Cisco Firepower 2-port 100G double-width network module installed, which is PID FPR9K-DNM-2X100G. The fix for this vulnerability is not an FXOS Software upgrade; it is an FPGA firmware upgrade.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco products:

Firepower 2100 Series
Firepower 4100 Series</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Indicators of Compromise" Type="General" Ordinal="4">On devices where this vulnerability is exploited, the input discard or overrrun interface counters will increase exponentially. The administrator can check for this condition by using the show interface command at the CLI. When one or both of these counters increment, this is an indication that no traffic is being processed on the interface.


Fp9000(fxos)# show interface eth2/1
Ethernet2/1 is up  Dedicated Interface    Hardware: 100000 Ethernet, address: 70db.9819.a7b4 (bia 70db.9819.a7b4)    Description: U: Uplink    .    .    .      RX      0 unicast packets  425 multicast packets  0 broadcast packets      425 input packets  57370 bytes      0 jumbo packets  0 storm suppression bytes      0 runts  0 giants  0 CRC  0 no buffer      0 input error  0 short frame  0 overrun   0 underrun  0 ignored      0 watchdog  0 bad etype drop  0 bad proto drop  0 if down drop      0 input with dribble  425 input discard            0 Rx pause
    The device may need to be rebooted to clear this condition. Contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) for further assistance.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">This vulnerability is fixed by an upgrade to the FPGA firmware. Customers are advised to follow the procedure outlined in the Firmware Upgrade ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/fxos/fxos241/cli-guide/b_CLI_ConfigGuide_FXOS_241/image_management.html#task_2279C01A2AF8466D80F0A5C0D129E1EB"] section of the Cisco Firepower 4100/9300 FXOS CLI Configuration Guide.

This procedure works for FXOS Software Releases 2.2.2 or later. A customer on an earlier release should upgrade to Software Release 2.2.2 (or later) or contact the Cisco TAC for assistance.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found during the resolution of a Cisco TAC support case.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190220-firpwr-dos</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Firepower 9000 Series Firepower 2-Port 100G Double-Width Network Module Queue Wedge Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower Extensible Operating System (FXOS)" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225888">Cisco Firepower Extensible Operating System (FXOS) </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco Firepower 9000 Series Firepower 2-Port 100G Double Width Network Module Queue Wedge Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvn57812</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in field-programmable gate array (FPGA) ingress buffer management for the Cisco Firepower 9000 Series with the Cisco Firepower 2-port 100G double-width network module (PID: FPR9K-DNM-2X100G) could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to cause a denial of service (DoS) condition. Manual intervention may be required before a device will resume normal operations.

The vulnerability is due to a logic error in the FPGA related to the processing of different types of input packets. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by being on the adjacent subnet and sending a crafted sequence of input packets to a specific interface on an affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause a queue wedge condition on the interface. When a wedge occurs, the affected device will stop processing any additional packets that are received on the wedged interface.
</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvn57812</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2019-1700</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225888</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>6.1</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:A/AC:H/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190220-firpwr-dos</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Firepower 9000 Series Firepower 2-Port 100G Double-Width Network Module Queue Wedge Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>