<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Vulnerabilities</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.2</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-04-07T15:48:35</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.1</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-04-15T15:38:41</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Added that the RV320 and RV325 hardware platforms are vulnerable. Added that RV016, RV042, and RV082 are not vulnerable. Added Cisco bug ID CSCvy01220 to advisory header and to the details for CVE-2021-1251.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.2</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-08-04T15:58:36</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated fixed release for CVE-2021-1251.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-04-07T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-08-04T15:58:36</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Multiple vulnerabilities exist in the Link Layer Discovery Protocol (LLDP) implementation for Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers. An unauthenticated, adjacent attacker could execute arbitrary code or cause an affected router to leak system memory or reload. A memory leak or device reload would cause a denial of service (DoS) condition on an affected device.

For more information about these vulnerabilities, see the Details ["#details"] section of this advisory.

Note: LLDP is a Layer 2 protocol. To exploit these vulnerabilities, an attacker must be in the same broadcast domain as the affected device (Layer 2 adjacent).

Cisco has released software updates that address these vulnerabilities. There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">These vulnerabilities affect the following Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers if they are running a vulnerable firmware release and have LLDP enabled:

RV132W ADSL2+ Wireless-N VPN Router
RV134W VDSL2 Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV160 VPN Router
RV160W Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV260 VPN Router
RV260P VPN Router with PoE
RV260W Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV320 Dual Gigabit WAN VPN Router
RV325 Dual Gigabit WAN VPN Router
RV340 Dual WAN Gigabit VPN Router
RV340W Dual WAN Gigabit Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV345 Dual WAN Gigabit VPN Router
RV345P Dual WAN Gigabit PoE VPN Router

For information about which Cisco firmware releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory.
  LLDP Configurations
For Cisco RV132W, RV134W, RV320, and RV325 Routers, LLDP is enabled by default on all LAN ports and WAN interfaces.

For the following Cisco Small Business Routers, LLDP is enabled by default on the LAN ports and disabled by default on the WAN interfaces:

RV160 VPN Router
RV160W Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV260 VPN Router
RV260P VPN Router with PoE
RV260W Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV340 Dual WAN Gigabit VPN Router
RV340W Dual WAN Gigabit Wireless-AC VPN Router
RV345 Dual WAN Gigabit VPN Router
RV345P Dual WAN Gigabit PoE VPN Router</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by these vulnerabilities.

Cisco has confirmed that these vulnerabilities do not affect the following Cisco products:

RV016 Multi-WAN VPN Router
RV042 Dual WAN VPN Router
RV042G Dual Gigabit WAN VPN Router
RV082 Dual WAN VPN Router</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">These vulnerabilities are not dependent on one another. Exploitation of one of the vulnerabilities is not required to exploit another vulnerability. In addition, a software release that is affected by one of the vulnerabilities may not be affected by the other vulnerabilities.

Details about the vulnerabilities are as follows:

CVE-2021-1309: Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Remote Code Execution and Denial of Service Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the LLDP implementation for Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to execute arbitrary code on an affected device or cause the device to reload.

This vulnerability is due to missing length validation of certain LLDP packet header fields. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a malicious LLDP packet to the targeted router. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute code on the affected router or cause it to reload unexpectedly, resulting in a DoS condition.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvw62392 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62392"], CSCvw62410 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62410"], CSCvw62413 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62413"], and CSCvw62416 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62416"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1309
Security Impact Rating (SIR): High
CVSS Base Score: 8.8
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:H

CVE-2021-1251: Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Memory Leak Denial of Service Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the LLDP implementation for Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to cause a memory leak on an affected device.

This vulnerability is due to missing length validation of certain LLDP packet header fields. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a malicious LLDP packet to the targeted router. A successful exploit could cause continuous memory consumption on an affected device and eventually cause it to reload, resulting in a DoS condition.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvw94339 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw94339"], CSCvw94341 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw94341"], CSCvw95016 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw95016"], CSCvw95017 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw95017"], and CSCvy01220 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvy01220"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1251
Security Impact Rating (SIR): High
CVSS Base Score: 7.4
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H

CVE-2021-1308: Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Denial of Service Vulnerability

A vulnerability in the LLDP implementation for Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to cause an affected router to reload unexpectedly.

This vulnerability is due to missing length validation of certain LLDP packet header fields. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a malicious LLDP packet to the targeted router. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause the affected router to reload unexpectedly, resulting in a DoS condition.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

Bug ID(s): CSCvw62395 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62395"], CSCvw62411 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62411"], CSCvw62417 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62417"], and CSCvw62418 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvw62418"]
CVE ID: CVE-2021-1308
Security Impact Rating (SIR): High
CVSS Base Score: 7.4
CVSS Vector: CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerabilities described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
      Fixed Releases
Customers are advised to upgrade to an appropriate fixed firmware release as indicated in the following table(s):
                                Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers              Fixed Releases                                              RV132W              1.0.1.15 and later                                  RV134W              1.0.1.21 and later                                  RV160, RV160W, RV260, RV260P, and RV260W              1.0.01.03 and later                                  RV320 and RV325              Refer to End-of-Sale and End-of-Life Announcement for the Cisco RV320 and RV325 Dual Gigabit WAN VPN Router ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/collateral/routers/small-business-rv-series-routers/eos-eol-notice-c51-743069.html"].                                  RV340, RV340W, RV345, and RV345P              1.0.03.22 and later1
1. The fixed release for CVE-2021-1251 that was listed in the original version of this advisory was found to be incomplete. To fix all vulnerabilities described in this advisory, upgrade to Release 1.0.03.22.
To download the firmware from the Software Center ["https://software.cisco.com/download/"] on Cisco.com, do the following:

Click Browse all.
Choose Routers &gt; Small Business Routers &gt; Small Business RV Series Routers.
Choose the appropriate router.
Choose Small Business Router Firmware.
Choose a release from the left pane of the product page.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerabilities that are described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">Cisco would like to thank Qian Chen of Qihoo 360 Nirvan Team for reporting these vulnerabilities.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Vulnerabilities</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Small Business RV Series Router Firmware" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-183630">Cisco Small Business RV Series Router Firmware </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1309</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvw62392</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvw62392,CSCvw62410,CSCvw62413,CSCvw62416</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1309</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-183630</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>8.8</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:U/C:H/I:H/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="2" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1308</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvw62395</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvw62395,CSCvw62411,CSCvw62417,CSCvw62418</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1308</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-183630</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.4</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="3" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1251</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvw94339</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvw94339,CSCvw94341,CSCvw95016,CSCvw95017,CSCvy01220</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1251</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-183630</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.4</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-rv-multi-lldp-u7e4chCe</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Small Business RV Series Routers Link Layer Discovery Protocol Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>