<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco Secure Web Appliance Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-wsa-prv-esc-nPzWZrQj</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.1</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2020-11-13T15:28:06</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.1</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-01-21T14:53:26</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Added new fix information for releases 10.1 and earlier. Updated the fixed release number for Release 12.0.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2020-11-18T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-01-21T14:53:26</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the log subscription subsystem of Cisco AsyncOS for the Cisco Secure Web Appliance (formerly Web Security Appliance) could allow an authenticated, local attacker to perform command injection and elevate privileges to root.

This vulnerability is due to insufficient validation of user-supplied input for the web interface and CLI. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by authenticating to the affected device and injecting scripting commands in the scope of the log subscription subsystem. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute arbitrary commands on the underlying operating system and elevate privileges to root.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-wsa-prv-esc-nPzWZrQj ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-wsa-prv-esc-nPzWZrQj"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects Cisco AsyncOS for the Secure Web Appliance, both virtual and hardware appliances.

For information about which Cisco software releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco products:

Secure Email (formerly Email Security Appliance), both virtual and hardware appliances
Secure Email and Web Manager (formerly Security Management Appliance), both virtual and hardware appliances</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Simplifying the Cisco portfolio includes the renaming of security products under one brand: Cisco Secure. For more information, see Meet Cisco Secure ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/security/secure-names.html"].</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
      Fixed Releases
Customers are advised to upgrade to an appropriate fixed software release as indicated in the following table:
        Cisco AsyncOS for Secure Web Appliance Major Release  First Fixed Release          10.1 and earlier  10.1.5-037      10.5  11.7.2-011      11.5  11.7.2-011      11.7  11.7.2-011      11.8  11.8.2-009      12.0  12.0.2-004      12.5  12.5.1-011
In most cases, the software can be upgraded over the network by using the System Upgrade options in the web interface of the Secure Web Appliance. To upgrade a device by using the web interface, do the following:

Choose System Administration &gt; System Upgrade.
Click Upgrade Options.
Choose Download and Install.
Choose the release to upgrade to.
In the Upgrade Preparation area, choose the appropriate options.
Click Proceed to begin the upgrade. A progress bar displays the status of the upgrade.

After the upgrade is complete, the device reboots.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found by Alvaro Gutierrez Quiles of Cisco during internal security testing.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-wsa-prv-esc-nPzWZrQj</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Secure Web Appliance Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Web Security Appliance (WSA)" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-189789">Cisco Web Security Appliance (WSA) </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2020-3367</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvs65863</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvs65863</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2020-3367</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-189789</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>5.3</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:L/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:U/C:L/I:L/A:L</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-wsa-prv-esc-nPzWZrQj</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Secure Web Appliance Privilege Escalation Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>