<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software GUI Configuration Denial of Service Vulnerabilities</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.1</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2019-04-17T16:15:26</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.1</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2019-04-18T18:04:38</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Corrected Fixed Software table to note recommended release 8.6, 8.7, and 8.8 as 8.8.120.0.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2019-04-17T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2019-04-18T18:04:38</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Multiple vulnerabilities in the administrative GUI configuration feature of Cisco Wireless LAN Controller (WLC) Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to cause the device to reload unexpectedly during device configuration when the administrator is using this GUI, causing a denial of service (DoS) condition on an affected device. The attacker would need to have valid administrator credentials on the device.

These vulnerabilities are due to incomplete input validation for unexpected configuration options that the attacker could submit while accessing the GUI configuration menus. An attacker could exploit these vulnerabilities by authenticating to the device and submitting crafted user input when using the administrative GUI configuration feature. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause the device to reload, resulting in a DoS condition.

These vulnerabilities have a Security Impact Rating (SIR) of High because they could be exploited when the software fix for the Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Cross-Site Request Forgery Vulnerability ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-csrf"] is not in place. In that case, an unauthenticated attacker who first exploits the cross-site request forgery vulnerability could perform arbitrary commands with the privileges of the administrator user by exploiting the vulnerabilities described in this advisory.

Cisco has released software updates that address these vulnerabilities. There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">These vulnerabilities affect Cisco Wireless LAN Controllers that are running a vulnerable software release.

For information about which Cisco WLC Software releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory.
  Determining the Cisco WLC Software Release
To determine which Cisco WLC Software release is running on a device, administrators can use the controller web interface or the CLI.

To use the web interface, do the following:

By using a browser, log in to the controller web interface.
Click the Monitor tab.
Click Summary in the left pane.
Under Controller Summary, the Software Version field shows the release number of the software that is currently running on the device.

To use the CLI, log in to the controller by using Telnet, issue the show sysinfo command, and then refer to the value in the Product Version field of the command output. The following example shows the command output for a device that is running Cisco WLC Software Release 8.3.102.0:


(wlc)&gt; show sysinfo
  Manufacturer's Name.............................. Cisco Systems Inc.  Product Name..................................... Cisco Controller  Product Version.................................. 8.3.102.0  Bootloader Version............................... 1.0.1
Field Recovery Image Version..................... 6.0.182.0  Firmware Version................................. FPGA 1.3, Env 1.6, USB console 1.27  Build Type....................................... DATA + WPS  .  .  .</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by these vulnerabilities.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities. As a mitigation, customers may choose to implement access control lists (ACLs) to filter or restrict management access to a configured device.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerabilities described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page, to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
  Fixed Releases
Customers should upgrade to an appropriate release ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"] as indicated in the table in this section. To help ensure a complete upgrade solution, consider that this advisory is part of a collection that includes the following advisories:

cisco-sa-20190417-aironet-shell ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-aironet-shell"]: Cisco Aironet Series Access Points Development Shell Access Vulnerability
cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-csrf ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-csrf"]: Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software Cross-Site Request Forgery Vulnerability
cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui"]: Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software GUI Configuration Denial of Service Vulnerabilities
 cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-iapp ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/ cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-iapp"]: Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software IAPP Message Handling Denial of Service Vulnerabilities

In the following table, the left column lists major Cisco software releases. The center column indicates whether a major release is affected by the vulnerabilities described in this advisory and the minor release that fixes the vulnerabilities described in this advisory and the vulnerability described in Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Cross-Site Request Forgery Vulnerability ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-csrf"]. The right column indicates whether a major release is affected by all the vulnerabilities described in this collection of advisories and which release includes fixes for those vulnerabilities.

Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software
                                Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Major Software Release              Recommended Release for These Vulnerabilities              Recommended Release for All Vulnerabilities Described in the Collection of Advisories                                  Prior to 8.01
              8.3.150.0               8.3.150.0
                                  8.01              8.3.150.0               8.3.150.0
                                  8.11              8.3.150.0              8.3.150.0
                                  8.21              8.3.150.0              8.3.150.0
                                  8.31              8.3.150.0              8.3.150.0
                                  8.4              8.5.140.0              8.5.140.0
                                  8.5              8.5.140.0              8.5.140.0
                                  8.6              8.8.111.0              8.8.120.0
                                  8.7              8.8.111.0
              8.8.120.0
                                  8.8              8.8.111.0
              8.8.120.0                                   8.9              Not vulnerable              Not vulnerable
                    1. Cisco bug IDs CSCve99212 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCve99212"] and CSCvf20684 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvf20684"] apply only to Software Release 8.4 and later.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerabilities that are described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">These vulnerabilities were found during internal security testing.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software GUI Configuration Denial of Service Vulnerabilities</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Wireless LAN Controller (WLC)" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-7368">Cisco Wireless LAN Controller (WLC) </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco Wireless LAN Controller GUI Configuration Denial of Service Vulnerabilities</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvf16322</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">Multiple vulnerabilities in the administrative GUI configuration feature of Cisco Wireless LAN Controller (WLC) Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to cause the device to reload unexpectedly during device configuration when the administrator is using this GUI, causing a denial of service (DoS) condition on an affected device. The attacker would need to have valid administrator credentials on the device.

These vulnerabilities are due to incomplete input validation for unexpected configuration options that the attacker could submit while accessing the GUI configuration menus. An attacker could exploit these vulnerabilities by authenticating to the device and submitting crafted user input when using the administrative GUI configuration feature. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause the device to reload, resulting in a DoS condition.

These vulnerabilities have a Security Impact Rating (SIR) of High because they could be exploited when the software fix for the Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Cross-Site Request Forgery Vulnerability ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-csrf"] is not in place. In that case, an unauthenticated attacker who first exploits the cross-site request forgery vulnerability could perform arbitrary commands with the privileges of the administrator user by exploiting the vulnerabilities described in this advisory.
</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvf16322,CSCve99744,CSCvd64417,CSCve58704,CSCve68131,CSCve82306,CSCve88013,CSCve90361,CSCve90365,CSCve91536,CSCve91601,CSCve92619,CSCve93039,CSCve93215,CSCve93547,CSCve94030,CSCve94052,CSCve94683,CSCve94821,CSCve94942,CSCve95046,CSCve95104,CSCve95848,CSCve95866,CSCve95898,CSCve95987,CSCve96534,CSCve96615,CSCve96858,CSCve96879,CSCve97734,CSCve97771,CSCve98357,CSCve98393,CSCve98434,CSCve99020,CSCve99072,CSCve99212,CSCvf01690,CSCvf02412,CSCvf06525,CSCvf08015,CSCvf15789,CSCvf16237,CSCvf16358,CSCvf20684,CSCvf27133,CSCvf27342,CSCvf42722,CSCvf47220,CSCvf47430,CSCvf54469,CSCvf57639,CSCvf58849,CSCvf59210,CSCvf59796,CSCvf59799,CSCvb35683,CSCvf47085,CSCvf47934</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2018-0248</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-7368</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>6.8</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:H/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address these vulnerabilities. As a mitigation, customers may choose to implement access control lists (ACLs) to filter or restrict management access to a configured device.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20190417-wlc-gui</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Wireless LAN Controller Software GUI Configuration Denial of Service Vulnerabilities</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>