<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco IOS XR Software IPv6 Flood Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-xripv6-spJem78K</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.0</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-03T15:01:08</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-02-03T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-02-03T16:00:00</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the IPv6 protocol handling of the management interfaces of Cisco IOS XR Software could allow an unauthenticated, adjacent attacker to cause an IPv6 flood on the management interface network of an affected device.

The vulnerability exists because the software incorrectly forwards IPv6 packets that have an IPv6 node-local multicast group address destination and are received on the management interfaces. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by connecting to the same network as the management interfaces and injecting IPv6 packets that have an IPv6 node-local multicast group address destination. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause an IPv6 flood on the corresponding network. Depending on the number of Cisco IOS XR Software nodes on that network segment, exploitation could cause excessive network traffic, resulting in network degradation or a denial of service (DoS) condition.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xripv6-spJem78K ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xripv6-spJem78K"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects Cisco devices if they are running a vulnerable release of Cisco IOS XR Software and the management interface is configured with both of the following:

An IPv6 address
The default IPv6 static route with next-hop on the management interface segment

For information about which Cisco software releases are vulnerable, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">If this vulnerability is exploited, the number of packets that are forwarded to the network is dependent on the number of Cisco IOS XR Software management interfaces that are connected to the network segment. The more Cisco IOS XR devices that have management interfaces and are connected to the same Layer 2 domain, the more packets that are forwarded on the Layer 2 segment. An excessive number of forwarded packets could result in network degradation and possibly cause a denial of service (DoS) condition on the network.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Removing the default IPv6 static route and adding a prefix-specific route would mitigate this vulnerability. For example, removing the default IPv6 static route and adding an IPv6 static route of 2000::/3 &lt;next hop&gt; would mitigate this vulnerability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:
https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
      Fixed Releases
Cisco fixed this vulnerability in Cisco IOS XR Software releases 6.7.3, 7.1.3, 7.2.2, and 7.3.1.

Cisco has released software maintenance upgrades (SMUs) to address this vulnerability. Customers who require SMUs for other platforms and releases are advised to contact their support organization.
        Cisco IOS XR Software Release  Platform  SMU Name          6.3.1  NCS1K  ncs1k-6.3.1.CSCvv45504      NCS1001  ncs1001-6.3.1.CSCvv45504      6.5.2  NCS1K  ncs1k-6.5.2.CSCvv45504      NCS1001  ncs1001-6.5.2.CSCvv45504</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found during the resolution of a Cisco TAC support case.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xripv6-spJem78K</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco IOS XR Software IPv6 Flood Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco IOS XR Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-5834">Cisco IOS XR Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1268</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvv45504</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvv45504</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1268</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-5834</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.4</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:A/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>Removing the default IPv6 static route and adding a prefix-specific route would mitigate this vulnerability. For example, removing the default IPv6 static route and adding an IPv6 static route of 2000::/3 &lt;next hop&gt; would mitigate this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xripv6-spJem78K</URL>
        <Description>Cisco IOS XR Software IPv6 Flood Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>