<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Sudo Privilege Escalation Vulnerability Affecting Cisco Products: January 2021</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-sudo-privesc-jan2021-qnYQfcM</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.15</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-01-29T21:36:53</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.1</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-01T21:03:13</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.2</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-02T21:20:38</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable. Note that Cisco FXOS Software was incorrectly listed as vulnerable in a previous version of the advisory; this has been corrected because Cisco has determined that this product is not affected by this vulnerability.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.3</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-03T20:08:23</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.4</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-04T21:03:43</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable. Note that Cisco Virtual Topology System (formerly Cisco Virtual Systems Operations Center) - VTSR VM was incorrectly listed as vulnerable in a previous version of the advisory; this has been corrected because Cisco has determined that this product is not affected by this vulnerability.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.5</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-05T19:44:53</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.6</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-08T20:04:13</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation and vulnerable products.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.7</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-10T19:49:23</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable. Note that Cisco has confirmed that Cisco Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) is not affected by this vulnerability. It was incorrectly listed as vulnerable in a previous version of the advisory.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.8</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-11T20:22:13</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.9</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-16T18:34:25</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.10</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-19T20:40:52</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.11</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-22T21:38:52</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of products under investigation, vulnerable products, and products confirmed not vulnerable. Note that upon further investigation Cisco has confirmed that Cisco Application Policy Infrastructure Controller (APIC) is not affected by this vulnerability. It was incorrectly listed as vulnerable in a previous version of the advisory.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.12</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-02-25T21:48:04</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of vulnerable products and products confirmed not vulnerable. Removed references to ongoing investigation.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.13</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-03-02T21:17:24</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the list of vulnerable products.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.14</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-03-11T20:49:19</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the lists of vulnerable products and products confirmed not vulnerable.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.15</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-03-16T20:43:10</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Updated the list of vulnerable products.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-01-29T21:30:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-03-16T20:43:10</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the command line parameter parsing code of Sudo could allow an authenticated, local attacker to execute commands or binaries with root privileges.

The vulnerability is due to improper parsing of command line parameters that may result in a heap-based buffer overflow. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by accessing a Unix shell on an affected device and then invoking the sudoedit command with crafted parameters or by executing a binary exploit. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to execute commands or binaries with root privileges.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sudo-privesc-jan2021-qnYQfcM ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sudo-privesc-jan2021-qnYQfcM"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Affected Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">Cisco investigated its product line to determine which products and services may be affected by this vulnerability.

The Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section includes Cisco bug IDs for each affected product. The bugs are accessible through the Cisco Bug Search Tool and contain additional platform-specific information, including workarounds (if available) and fixed software releases.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="3">The following table lists Cisco products that are affected by the vulnerability that is described in this advisory. If a future release date is indicated for software, the date provided represents an estimate based on all information known to Cisco as of the Last Updated date at the top of the advisory. Availability dates are subject to change based on a number of factors, including satisfactory testing results and delivery of other priority features and fixes. If no version or date is listed for an affected component (indicated by a blank field and/or an advisory designation of Interim), Cisco is continuing to evaluate the fix and will update the advisory as additional information becomes available. After the advisory is marked Final, customers should refer to the associated Cisco bug(s) for further details. Unless otherwise documented, all software releases prior to the first fixed release are to be considered affected by this vulnerability.
        Product  Cisco Bug ID  Fixed Release Availability ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"]      Network Management and Provisioning      Cisco Elastic Services Controller (ESC)  CSCvx18712 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18712"]  ESC-5.4.0.86 (Available)      Cisco Prime Collaboration Provisioning  CSCvx18714 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18714"]  12.6.SU3 (Apr 2021)      Cisco Prime Service Catalog Virtual Appliance  CSCvx18724 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18724"]  See the bug for update information.      Cisco Smart Net Total Care - On-Premises  CSCvx18702 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18702"]  2.1.0.1 (Mar 2021)      Cisco Smart Software Manager On-Prem  CSCvx22363 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx22363"]  8-202102 (Mar 2021)      Routing and Switching - Enterprise and Service Provider      Cisco Nexus 3000 Series Switches  CSCvx18710 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18710"]  7.0(3)I7(9) (Available)1
9.3.7 (Available)
10.1.1 (Available)      Cisco Nexus 7000 Series Switches  CSCvx18709 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18709"]  8.4.4 (Available)      Cisco Nexus 9000 Series Switches in standalone NX-OS mode  CSCvx18710 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18710"]  7.0(3)I7(9) (Available)1
9.3.7 (Available)
10.1.1 (Available)      Cisco Redundancy and Configuration Manager (for 4G/5G
StarOS UserPlane)  CSCvx19139 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx19139"]  21.23.0 (Mar 2021)
21.22.uax (Apr 2021)      Unified Computing      Cisco UCS Director  CSCvx18705 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18705"]  6.8 (Mar 2021)      Voice and Unified Communications Devices      Cisco Paging Server (InformaCast)  CSCvx18737 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx18737"]  12.22.1 (Mar 2021)
14.0.1 (Mar 2021)      Cisco Cloud Hosted Services      Cisco Common Services Platform Collector  CSCvx20991 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx20991"]  2.9.0.2 (Available)
See the bug for 2.8 update information.      Cisco CX Cloud Agent Software  CSCvx49685 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx49685"]  1.3 (Available)      Cisco Ultra Cloud  CSCvx21182 ["https://tools.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvx21182"]  2020.02.1.i33 (Mar 2021)
1. See the bug for additional operations that may be required to fully address this vulnerability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="4">Only products and services listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vulnerable"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Products that do not offer the capability for users to access an interactive terminal or to execute custom binaries in the context of the underlying Unix operating system or of a guest Unix operating system do not present an attack vector for the exploitation of this vulnerability and therefore are not considered vulnerable.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following products and services:

Collaboration and Social Media

Cisco Webex Meetings Server

Endpoint Clients and Client Software

Cisco Jabber Guest

Network and Content Security Devices

Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software
Cisco FXOS Software
Cisco Firepower Threat Defense (FTD)
Cisco Identity Services Engine (ISE)

Network Management and Provisioning

Cisco Application Policy Infrastructure Controller (APIC)
Cisco Connected Mobile Experiences
Cisco Data Center Network Manager (DCNM)
Cisco Evolved Programmable Network Manager
Cisco Policy Suite
Cisco Prime Access Registrar
Cisco Prime Infrastructure
Cisco Prime Network Change and Configuration Management
Cisco Virtual Topology System (formerly Cisco Virtual Systems Operations Center) - VTSR VM
Cisco Virtualized Infrastructure Manager (VIM)

Routing and Switching - Enterprise and Service Provider

Cisco 8000 Series Routers
Cisco ASR 5000 Series
Cisco ASR 9000 Aggregation Services Routers Series
Cisco Carrier Routing System (CRS)
Cisco Connected Grid Routers
Cisco DNA Center
Cisco IOS XRv 9000 Router
Cisco IOS and IOS XE Software
Cisco MDS 9000 Series Multilayer Switches
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 540 Series Routers
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 560 Series Routers
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 1000 Series
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 4000 Series
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 5000 Series
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 5500 Series
Cisco Network Convergence System (NCS) 6000 Series Routers
Cisco Nexus 9000 Series Fabric Switches in Application Centric Infrastructure (ACI) mode
Cisco ONS 15454 Series Multiservice Provisioning Platforms
Cisco SD-WAN vManage
Cisco Stealthwatch Endpoint Concentrator
Cisco Stealthwatch Flow Collector NetFlow
Cisco Stealthwatch Flow Collector sFlow
Cisco Stealthwatch Flow Sensor
Cisco Stealthwatch Management Console (SMC)
Cisco Stealthwatch UDP Director
Cisco Virtual Packet Core

Unified Computing

Cisco Enterprise NFV Infrastructure Software (NFVIS)

Voice and Unified Communications Devices

Cisco ATA 190 Analog Telephone Adapter
Cisco SPA112 2-Port Phone Adapter
Cisco SPA122 Analog Telephone Adapter (ATA) with Router
Cisco SPA232D Multi-Line DECT Analog Telephone Adapter (ATA)

Video, Streaming, TelePresence, and Transcoding Devices

Cisco Expressway Series
Cisco TelePresence Video Communication Server (VCS)
Cisco Video Surveillance Media Server

Wireless

Cisco Mobility Services Engine

Cisco Cloud Hosted Services

Cisco Jasper Control Center</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">Any workarounds will be documented in the product-specific Cisco bugs, which are identified in the Vulnerable Products ["#vulnerable"] section of this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">For information about fixed software releases ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], consult the Cisco bugs identified in the Vulnerable Products ["#vulnerable"] section of this advisory.

When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">On January 26th, the Qualys Research Team disclosed the vulnerability in a public advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sudo-privesc-jan2021-qnYQfcM</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Sudo Privilege Escalation Vulnerability Affecting Cisco Products: January 2021</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-3156</Title>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-3156</CVE>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>Any workarounds will be documented in the product-specific Cisco bugs, which are identified in the Vulnerable Products ["#vulnerable"] section of this advisory.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-sudo-privesc-jan2021-qnYQfcM</URL>
        <Description>Sudo Privilege Escalation Vulnerability Affecting Cisco Products: January 2021</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>