<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance Software and Firepower Threat Defense Software SNMP Access Control Vulnerability</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-asaftd-snmpaccess-M6yOweq3</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.0</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-10-27T15:39:27</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-10-27T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-10-27T16:00:00</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Simple Network Management Protocol version 3 (SNMPv3) access control functionality of Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software and Cisco Firepower Threat Defense (FTD) Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to query SNMP data.

This vulnerability is due to ineffective access control. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending an SNMPv3 query to an affected device from a host that is not permitted by the SNMPv3 access control list. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to send an SNMP query to an affected device and retrieve information from the device. The attacker would need valid credentials to perform the SNMP query.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-asaftd-snmpaccess-M6yOweq3 ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-asaftd-snmpaccess-M6yOweq3"]

This advisory is part of the October 2021 release of the Cisco ASA, FTD, and FMC Security Advisory Bundled publication. For a complete list of the advisories and links to them, see Cisco Event Response: October 2021 Cisco ASA, FMC, and FTD Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-74773"].</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">At the time of publication, this vulnerability affected Cisco Adaptive Security Appliances and Cisco Firepower Appliances if they were running a vulnerable release of Cisco ASA Software or FTD Software and had SNMPv3 access control configured.

For information about which Cisco software releases were vulnerable at the time of publication, see the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this advisory. See the Details section in the bug ID(s) at the top of this advisory for the most complete and current information.
  Determine the Device Configuration
To determine whether an SNMPv3 user-based access control entry is configured, run the show running-config snmp-server CLI command and check for the presence of version 3 in the output. The following output shows a configured SNMPv3 access entry:


ASA# show running-config snmp-server | include host
snmp-server host internalMgmt 10.10.10.10 version 3 snmpUser
snmp-server host internalMgmt 10.11.12.13 community snmpCommunity
ASA#</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect Cisco Firepower Management Center (FMC) Software.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
      Fixed Releases
At the time of publication, the release information in the following table(s) was accurate. See the Details section in the bug ID(s) at the top of this advisory for the most complete and current information.

The left column lists Cisco software releases, and the right column indicates whether a release was affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and which release included the fix for this vulnerability.

ASA Software
                                Cisco ASA Software Release              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability                                              Earlier than 9.81              Not vulnerable.                                  9.8              Not vulnerable.                                  9.91
              Not vulnerable.                                  9.101
              Not vulnerable.                                  9.12              Not vulnerable.                                  9.131              Not vulnerable.                                  9.14              9.14.2.4                                  9.15              9.15.1.7                                  9.16              Not vulnerable.
1. Cisco ASA Software releases 9.7 and earlier as well as releases 9.9, 9.10, and 9.13 have reached end of software maintenance ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/eos-eol-listing.html"]. Customers are advised to migrate to a supported release that includes the fix for this vulnerability.
FTD Software
                                Cisco FTD Software Release              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability                                              6.2.2 and earlier1              Not vulnerable.                                  6.2.3              Not vulnerable.                                  6.3.01              Not vulnerable.                                  6.4.0              6.4.0.13 (Nov 2021)                                  6.5.01              Migrate to a fixed release.                                  6.6.0              6.6.5                                  6.7.0              6.7.0.1                                  7.0.0              Not vulnerable.
1. Cisco FMC and FTD Software releases 6.2.2 and earlier, as well as releases 6.3.0 and 6.5.0, have reached end of software maintenance ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/eos-eol-listing.html"]. Customers are advised to migrate to a supported release that includes the fix for this vulnerability.
For instructions on upgrading your FTD device, see Cisco Firepower Management Center Upgrade Guide ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/security/firepower/upgrade/fpmc-upgrade-guide/getting_started.html"].

The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) validates only the affected and fixed release information that is documented in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco PSIRT is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">This vulnerability was found during internal security testing.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-asaftd-snmpaccess-M6yOweq3</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance Software and Firepower Threat Defense Software SNMP Access Control Vulnerability</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
    <cvrf:Reference>
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-74773</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Event Response: October 2021 Cisco ASA, FMC, and FTD Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software" Type="Product Name">
        <Branch Name="9.14" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="9.14.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="9.14.1.10" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="9.14.1.6" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="9.14.1.15" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="9.14.1.19" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="9.14.1.30" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="9.14.2" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="9.15" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="9.15.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 2100 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 1000 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 9000 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 4100 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software Platform Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-6588">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software" Type="Product Name">
        <Branch Name="6.6" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="6.6.0" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="6.6.0.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
          <Branch Name="6.6.1" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="6.7" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="6.7.0" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 2100 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277392">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 1000 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277393">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277437">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277438">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 9000 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277440">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower 4100 Series" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277441">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower NGFW Virtual" Type="Product Name">
          <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-277464">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software Platform Cisco Firepower NGFW Virtual</FullProductName>
        </Branch>
      </Branch>
      <Branch Name="Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-220203">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278380">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278380:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278725">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278725:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.10 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278754">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278754:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.6 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278807">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278807:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.15 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-279344">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-279344:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.19 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280409">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280409:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.1.30 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281571">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281571:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.14.2 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277392">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277393">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277437">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277438">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277440">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277441">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277511" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-281575">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-281575:277511">Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance (ASA) Software 9.15.1 when installed on Cisco Adaptive Security Virtual Appliance (ASAv)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277392">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277393">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277437">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277438">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277440">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277441">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277464" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-225862">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-225862:277464">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower NGFW Virtual</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277392">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277393">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277437">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277438">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277440">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277441">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277464" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-278885">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-278885:277464">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.0.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower NGFW Virtual</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277392">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277393">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277437">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277438">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277440">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277441">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277464" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280013">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280013:277464">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.6.1 when installed on Cisco Firepower NGFW Virtual</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277392" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277392">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 2100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277393" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277393">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 1000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277437" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277437">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco ASA 5500-X Series Firewalls</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277438" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277438">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco 3000 Series Industrial Security Appliances (ISA)</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277440" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277440">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 9000 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277441" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277441">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower 4100 Series</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
    <Relationship RelatesToProductReference="CVRFPID-277464" RelationType="Installed On" ProductReference="CVRFPID-280664">
      <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-280664:277464">Cisco Firepower Threat Defense Software 6.7.0 when installed on Cisco Firepower NGFW Virtual</FullProductName>
    </Relationship>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-34794</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvw31710</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvw31710,CSCvw51436,CSCvv49739</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-34794</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-220203</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-225862:277464</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278885:277464</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280013:277464</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280664:277464</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278380:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278725:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278754:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-278807:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-279344:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-280409:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281571:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277392</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277393</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277437</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277438</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277440</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277441</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-281575:277511</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-6588</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>5.3</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:L/PR:N/UI:N/S:U/C:N/I:L/A:N</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-asaftd-snmpaccess-M6yOweq3</URL>
        <Description>Cisco Adaptive Security Appliance Software and Firepower Threat Defense Software SNMP Access Control Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>