<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco IOS XR Software Border Gateway Protocol Resource Public Key Infrastructure Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-xrbgp-rpki-dos-gvmjqxbk</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.0</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2021-09-08T15:43:07</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2021-09-08T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2021-09-08T16:00:00</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the implementation of the Resource Public Key Infrastructure (RPKI) feature of Cisco IOS XR Software could allow an unauthenticated, remote attacker to cause the Border Gateway Protocol (BGP) process to crash, resulting in a denial of service (DoS) condition.

This vulnerability is due to the incorrect handling of a specific RPKI to Router (RTR) Protocol packet header. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by compromising the RPKI validator server and sending a specifically crafted RTR packet to an affected device. Alternatively, the attacker could use man-in-the-middle techniques to impersonate the RPKI validator server and send a specifically crafted RTR response packet over the established RTR TCP connection to the affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause a DoS condition because the BGP process could constantly restart and BGP routing could become unstable.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xrbgp-rpki-dos-gvmjqxbk ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xrbgp-rpki-dos-gvmjqxbk"]

This advisory is part of the September 2021 release of the Cisco IOS XR Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication. For a complete list of the advisories and links to them, see Cisco Event Response: September 2021 Cisco IOS XR Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-74637"].</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">At the time of publication, this vulnerability affected Cisco devices if they were running Cisco IOS XR Software releases 4.3.0 through 7.3.0 and had RPKI configured and in use.

See the Details section in the bug ID(s) at the top of this advisory for the most complete and current information.

Determine the RPKI Device Configuration

To determine if an RPKI server is configured, issue the show running-config router bgp CLI command. If the rpki server command is displayed, as shown in the following example, the device could be vulnerable:


iosxr# show running-config router bgp
.
.
.
 rpki server 192.168.1.100

Then, to determine if there is an active RPKI server, issue the show bgp rpki server summary CLI command. If an RPKI server TCP connection is in ESTAB state, as shown in the following example, the device is affected by this vulnerability:


iosxr# show bgp rpki server summary
Wed Aug 13 13:25:04.368 utc
  Hostname/Address        Transport       State           Time            ROAs (IPv4/IPv6)  10.112.255.14           TCP:323         CONNECT         00:00:06        N/A  2001:400:6:1::1         TCP:323         ESTAB           01:06:51        181152/30503

Note: If the command does not return output, RPKI is not configured. However, if the command returns output but none of the RPKI servers have a connection in ESTAB state, the device could become vulnerable if the connection becomes established.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco products:

IOS Software
IOS XE Software
NX-OS Software</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="4">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

However, administrators can remove the RPKI configuration as a mitigation. If RPKI servers are either not in use or removed from the configuration, the device is considered not vulnerable. The decision to remove the RPKI configuration needs careful consideration.

While this mitigation has been deployed and was proven successful in a test environment, customers should determine the applicability and effectiveness in their own environment and under their own use conditions. Customers should be aware that any workaround or mitigation that is implemented may negatively impact the functionality or performance of their network based on intrinsic customer deployment scenarios and limitations. Customers should not deploy any workarounds or mitigations before first evaluating the applicability to their own environment and any impact to such environment.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="5">When considering software upgrades ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/resources/security_vulnerability_policy.html#fixes"], customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
      Fixed Releases
At the time of publication, the following Cisco IOS XR Software releases contained the fix for this vulnerability:

7.3.1 and later
7.3.15 and later
7.4.1 and later

At the time of publication, Cisco had released the following SMUs to address this vulnerability. Customers who require SMUs for platforms or releases that are not listed are advised to contact their support organization.
        Cisco IOS XR Software Release  Platform  SMU Name          6.5.3  ASR9K-PX  asr9k-px-6.5.3.CSCvx04451      6.7.4  CRS-PX  hfr-px-6.7.4.CSCvx04451      7.0.2  ASR9K-X64  asr9k-x64-7.0.2.CSCvx04451      7.1.2  ASR9K-X64  asr9k-x64-7.1.2.CSCvx04451
See the Details section in the bug ID(s) at the top of this advisory for the most complete and current information, including SMU availability.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="6">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="7">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="8">This vulnerability was found during the resolution of a Cisco TAC support case.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="9">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xrbgp-rpki-dos-gvmjqxbk</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco IOS XR Software Border Gateway Protocol Resource Public Key Infrastructure Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
    <cvrf:Reference>
      <cvrf:URL>http://tools.cisco.com/security/center/viewErp.x?alertId=ERP-74637</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco Event Response: September  2021 Cisco IOS XR  Software Security Advisory Bundled Publication</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco IOS XR Software" Type="Product Name">
        <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-5834">Cisco IOS XR Software </FullProductName>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>vuln-CVE-2021-1440</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvx04451</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="1">CSCvx04451</Note>
      <Note Title="Affected Product Comprehensiveness" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">Complete.</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2021-1440</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-5834</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>6.8</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.1/AV:N/AC:H/PR:N/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

However, administrators can remove the RPKI configuration as a mitigation. If RPKI servers are either not in use or removed from the configuration, the device is considered not vulnerable. The decision to remove the RPKI configuration needs careful consideration.

While this mitigation has been deployed and was proven successful in a test environment, customers should determine the applicability and effectiveness in their own environment and under their own use conditions. Customers should be aware that any workaround or mitigation that is implemented may negatively impact the functionality or performance of their network based on intrinsic customer deployment scenarios and limitations. Customers should not deploy any workarounds or mitigations before first evaluating the applicability to their own environment and any impact to such environment.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-xrbgp-rpki-dos-gvmjqxbk</URL>
        <Description>Cisco IOS XR Software Border Gateway Protocol Resource Public Key Infrastructure Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>