<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cvrf:cvrfdoc xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:cvrf-common="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/common" xmlns:cvrf="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/cvrf">
  <cvrf:DocumentTitle>Cisco NX-OS Software Authenticated Simple Network Management Protocol Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:DocumentTitle>
  <cvrf:DocumentType>Cisco Security Advisory</cvrf:DocumentType>
  <cvrf:DocumentPublisher Type="Vendor">
    <cvrf:ContactDetails>Emergency Support:
+1 877 228 7302 (toll-free within North America)
+1 408 525 6532 (International direct-dial)
Non-emergency Support:
Email: psirt@cisco.com
Support requests that are received via e-mail are typically acknowledged within 48 hours.</cvrf:ContactDetails>
    <cvrf:IssuingAuthority>Cisco product security incident response is the responsibility of the Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT). The Cisco PSIRT is a dedicated, global team that manages the receipt, investigation, and public reporting of security vulnerability information that is related to Cisco products and networks. The on-call Cisco PSIRT works 24x7 with Cisco customers, independent security researchers, consultants, industry organizations, and other vendors to identify possible security issues with Cisco products and networks.
More information can be found in Cisco Security Vulnerability Policy available at http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html</cvrf:IssuingAuthority>
  </cvrf:DocumentPublisher>
  <cvrf:DocumentTracking>
    <cvrf:Identification>
      <cvrf:ID>cisco-sa-20181017-nxos-snmp</cvrf:ID>
    </cvrf:Identification>
    <cvrf:Status>Final</cvrf:Status>
    <cvrf:Version>1.0</cvrf:Version>
    <cvrf:RevisionHistory>
      <cvrf:Revision>
        <cvrf:Number>1.0</cvrf:Number>
        <cvrf:Date>2018-10-17T15:21:24</cvrf:Date>
        <cvrf:Description>Initial public release.</cvrf:Description>
      </cvrf:Revision>
    </cvrf:RevisionHistory>
    <cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>2018-10-17T16:00:00</cvrf:InitialReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>2018-10-17T15:21:24</cvrf:CurrentReleaseDate>
    <cvrf:Generator>
      <cvrf:Engine>TVCE</cvrf:Engine>
    </cvrf:Generator>
  </cvrf:DocumentTracking>
  <cvrf:DocumentNotes>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) input packet processor of Cisco NX-OS Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to cause the SNMP application of an affected device to restart unexpectedly.

The vulnerability is due to improper validation of SNMP protocol data units (PDUs) in SNMP packets. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted SNMP packet to an affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause the SNMP application to restart multiple times, leading to a system-level restart and a denial of service (DoS) condition.

Cisco has released software updates that address this vulnerability. There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

This advisory is available at the following link:
https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20181017-nxos-snmp ["https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20181017-nxos-snmp"]</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerable Products" Type="General" Ordinal="2">This vulnerability affects the following Cisco products if they are running a vulnerable release of Cisco NX-OS Software:

Nexus 3000 Series Switches
Nexus 3600 Platform Switches
Nexus 9000 Series Switches in standalone NX-OS mode
Nexus 9500 R-Series Line Cards and Fabric Modules

The only vulnerable software release for Nexus 3000 Series Switches and for Nexus 9000 Series Switches in standalone NX-OS mode is 7.0(3)I7(3).

The only vulnerable software release for Nexus 3600 Platform Switches and Nexus 9500 R-Series Line Cards and Fabric Modules is 7.0(3)F3(4).

Refer to the Fixed Software ["#fs"] section of this security advisory for more information about affected releases.
  Determining the Status of SNMP
Administrators can determine whether SNMP is running on a device by using the show running-config snmp command in the device CLI. If the command returns output, SNMP is configured.


nxos-switch# show running-config snmp
.  .  .  snmp-server user admin network-admin auth md5 ***** priv ***** localizedkey  snmp-server community community-string group network-admin</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Products Confirmed Not Vulnerable" Type="General" Ordinal="3">Only products listed in the Vulnerable Products ["#vp"] section of this advisory are known to be affected by this vulnerability.

Cisco has confirmed that this vulnerability does not affect the following Cisco products:

Firepower 2100 Series
Firepower 4100 Series Next-Generation Firewall
Firepower 9300 Security Appliance
MDS 9000 Series Multilayer Switches
Nexus 1000V Switch for Microsoft Hyper-V
Nexus 1000V Switch for VMware vSphere
Nexus 2000 Series Switches
Nexus 3500 Platform Switches
Nexus 5500 Platform Switches
Nexus 5600 Platform Switches
Nexus 6000 Series Switches
Nexus 7000 Series Switches
Nexus 7700 Series Switches
Nexus 9000 Series Fabric Switches in Application Centric Infrastructure (ACI) mode
Unified Computing System (UCS) 6100 Series Fabric Interconnects
UCS 6200 Series Fabric Interconnects
UCS 6300 Series Fabric Interconnects
UCS 6400 Series Fabric Interconnects</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Details" Type="General" Ordinal="4">SNMP is an application-layer protocol that provides a standardized framework and a common language for monitoring and managing devices in a network. It defines a message format for communication between SNMP managers and agents.

An SNMP agent gathers data from the SNMP MIB, which is the repository of information about device parameters and network data. It also responds to requests from an SNMP manager to get or set data. An SNMP agent contains MIB variables for which values can be requested or changed by an SNMP manager by using get or set operations.

This vulnerability affects all versions of SNMP supported on the device—Versions 1, 2c, and 3. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a specific SNMP packet to an affected device via IPv4 or IPv6. Only traffic directed to the affected system can be used to exploit this vulnerability.

To exploit this vulnerability via SNMP Version 2c or earlier, the attacker must know the SNMP read-only community string for the affected system. A community string is a password that is applied to a device to restrict both read-only and read-write access to the SNMP data on the device. These community strings, as with all passwords, should be chosen carefully to ensure that they are not trivial. They should also be changed at regular intervals and in accordance with network security policies. For example, the strings should be changed when a network administrator changes roles or leaves the organization.

To exploit this vulnerability via SNMP Version 3, the attacker must have user credentials for the affected system.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Workarounds" Type="General" Ordinal="5">There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

As a mitigation for the vulnerability that is described in this advisory, administrators can configure an access control list (ACL) on an SNMP community. This ACL will filter incoming SNMP requests to ensure that SNMP polling is performed only by trusted SNMP clients. In the following example, the device will accept incoming SNMP requests only from the trusted hosts 192.168.1.2 and 192.168.1.3:


switch# show access-list acl_for_snmp
IPV4 ACL acl_for_snmp
  10 permit udp 192.168.1.2/32 192.168.1.3/32 eq snmp

To implement the preceding ACL, administrators can add it to the snmp-server community configuration command:


switch# show running-config snmp
snmp-server community mycompany   use-acl acl_for_snmp

For additional information about configuring ACLs to filter incoming SNMP requests, see Filtering SNMP Requests ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus5000/sw/system_management/b_Cisco_Nexus_5000_Series_NX-OS_System_Management_Configuration_Guide/Cisco_Nexus_5000_Series_NX-OS_System_Management_Configuration_Guide_chapter9.html#task_D3862190751F4B1A9F5353B015A888A7"] in the Cisco NX-OS configuration guide.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Fixed Software" Type="General" Ordinal="6">Cisco has released free software updates that address the vulnerability described in this advisory. Customers may only install and expect support for software versions and feature sets for which they have purchased a license. By installing, downloading, accessing, or otherwise using such software upgrades, customers agree to follow the terms of the Cisco software license:  https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/products/end-user-license-agreement.html"]

Additionally, customers may only download software for which they have a valid license, procured from Cisco directly, or through a Cisco authorized reseller or partner. In most cases this will be a maintenance upgrade to software that was previously purchased. Free security software updates do not entitle customers to a new software license, additional software feature sets, or major revision upgrades.

When considering software upgrades, customers are advised to regularly consult the advisories for Cisco products, which are available from the Cisco Security Advisories and Alerts page ["https://www.cisco.com/go/psirt"], to determine exposure and a complete upgrade solution.

In all cases, customers should ensure that the devices to be upgraded contain sufficient memory and confirm that current hardware and software configurations will continue to be supported properly by the new release. If the information is not clear, customers are advised to contact the Cisco Technical Assistance Center (TAC) or their contracted maintenance providers.
  Customers Without Service Contracts
Customers who purchase directly from Cisco but do not hold a Cisco service contract and customers who make purchases through third-party vendors but are unsuccessful in obtaining fixed software through their point of sale should obtain upgrades by contacting the Cisco TAC: https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/support/web/tsd-cisco-worldwide-contacts.html"]

Customers should have the product serial number available and be prepared to provide the URL of this advisory as evidence of entitlement to a free upgrade.
  Fixed Releases
In the following tables, the left column lists releases of Cisco NX-OS Software. The right column indicates whether a release is affected by the vulnerability described in this advisory and the first release that includes the fix for this vulnerability.

Nexus 3000 Series Switches and 9000 Series Switches in Standalone NX-OS Mode: CSCvj70029 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvj70029"]
                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability                                              Prior to 7.0(3)I5
              Not vulnerable                                  7.0(3)I5               Not vulnerable
                                  7.0(3)I6               Not vulnerable                                                7.0(3)I7              7.0(3)I7(4)
                                  9.2(1)              Not vulnerable

Nexus 3600 Platform Switches and 9500 R-Series Line Cards and Fabric Modules: CSCvj70029 ["https://bst.cloudapps.cisco.com/bugsearch/bug/CSCvj70029"]

                                Cisco NX-OS Software Release              First Fixed Release for This Vulnerability                                              7.0(3)              Software Maintenance Upgrades (SMUs) 7.0(3)F3(4)                                  9.2(1)              Not vulnerable</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Vulnerability Policy" Type="General" Ordinal="7">To learn about Cisco security vulnerability disclosure policies and publications, see the Security Vulnerability Policy ["http://www.cisco.com/web/about/security/psirt/security_vulnerability_policy.html"]. This document also contains instructions for obtaining fixed software and receiving security vulnerability information from Cisco.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Exploitation and Public Announcements" Type="General" Ordinal="8">The Cisco Product Security Incident Response Team (PSIRT) is not aware of any public announcements or malicious use of the vulnerability that is described in this advisory.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Source" Type="General" Ordinal="9">This vulnerability was found during internal security testing.</cvrf:Note>
    <cvrf:Note Title="Legal Disclaimer" Type="Legal Disclaimer" Ordinal="10">THIS DOCUMENT IS PROVIDED ON AN "AS IS" BASIS AND DOES NOT IMPLY ANY KIND OF GUARANTEE OR WARRANTY, INCLUDING THE WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY OR FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR USE. YOUR USE OF THE INFORMATION ON THE DOCUMENT OR MATERIALS LINKED FROM THE DOCUMENT IS AT YOUR OWN RISK. CISCO RESERVES THE RIGHT TO CHANGE OR UPDATE THIS DOCUMENT AT ANY TIME.

A standalone copy or paraphrase of the text of this document that omits the distribution URL is an uncontrolled copy and may lack important information or contain factual errors. The information in this document is intended for end users of Cisco products.</cvrf:Note>
  </cvrf:DocumentNotes>
  <cvrf:DocumentReferences>
    <cvrf:Reference Type="Self">
      <cvrf:URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20181017-nxos-snmp</cvrf:URL>
      <cvrf:Description>Cisco NX-OS Software Authenticated Simple Network Management Protocol Denial of Service Vulnerability</cvrf:Description>
    </cvrf:Reference>
  </cvrf:DocumentReferences>
  <ProductTree xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/prod">
    <Branch Name="Cisco" Type="Vendor">
      <Branch Name="Cisco NX-OS Software" Type="Product Name">
        <Branch Name="7.0(3)F3" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="7.0(3)F3(4)" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-239636">Cisco NX-OS Software 7.0(3)F3(4)</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
        <Branch Name="7.0(3)I7" Type="Product Version">
          <Branch Name="7.0(3)I7(3)" Type="Service Pack">
            <FullProductName ProductID="CVRFPID-239479">Cisco NX-OS Software 7.0(3)I7(3)</FullProductName>
          </Branch>
        </Branch>
      </Branch>
    </Branch>
  </ProductTree>
  <Vulnerability Ordinal="1" xmlns="http://docs.oasis-open.org/csaf/ns/csaf-cvrf/v1.2/vuln">
    <Title>Cisco NX-OS Software Authenticated Simple Network Management Protocol Denial of Service Vulnerability</Title>
    <ID SystemName="Cisco Bug ID">CSCvj70029</ID>
    <Notes>
      <Note Title="Summary" Type="Summary" Ordinal="1">A vulnerability in the Simple Network Management Protocol (SNMP) input packet processor of Cisco NX-OS Software could allow an authenticated, remote attacker to cause the SNMP application of an affected device to restart unexpectedly.

The vulnerability is due to improper validation of SNMP protocol data units (PDUs) in SNMP packets. An attacker could exploit this vulnerability by sending a crafted SNMP packet to an affected device. A successful exploit could allow the attacker to cause the SNMP application to restart multiple times, leading to a system-level restart and a denial of service (DoS) condition.
</Note>
      <Note Title="Cisco Bug IDs" Type="Other" Ordinal="2">CSCvj70029</Note>
    </Notes>
    <CVE>CVE-2018-0456</CVE>
    <ProductStatuses>
      <Status Type="Known Affected">
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-239479</ProductID>
        <ProductID>CVRFPID-239636</ProductID>
      </Status>
    </ProductStatuses>
    <CVSSScoreSets>
      <ScoreSetV3>
        <BaseScoreV3>7.7</BaseScoreV3>
        <VectorV3>CVSS:3.0/AV:N/AC:L/PR:L/UI:N/S:C/C:N/I:N/A:H</VectorV3>
      </ScoreSetV3>
    </CVSSScoreSets>
    <Remediations>
      <Remediation Type="Workaround">
        <Description>There are no workarounds that address this vulnerability.

As a mitigation for the vulnerability that is described in this advisory, administrators can configure an access control list (ACL) on an SNMP community. This ACL will filter incoming SNMP requests to ensure that SNMP polling is performed only by trusted SNMP clients. In the following example, the device will accept incoming SNMP requests only from the trusted hosts 192.168.1.2 and 192.168.1.3:


switch# show access-list acl_for_snmp
IPV4 ACL acl_for_snmp
  10 permit udp 192.168.1.2/32 192.168.1.3/32 eq snmp

To implement the preceding ACL, administrators can add it to the snmp-server community configuration command:


switch# show running-config snmp
snmp-server community mycompany   use-acl acl_for_snmp

For additional information about configuring ACLs to filter incoming SNMP requests, see Filtering SNMP Requests ["https://www.cisco.com/c/en/us/td/docs/switches/datacenter/nexus5000/sw/system_management/b_Cisco_Nexus_5000_Series_NX-OS_System_Management_Configuration_Guide/Cisco_Nexus_5000_Series_NX-OS_System_Management_Configuration_Guide_chapter9.html#task_D3862190751F4B1A9F5353B015A888A7"] in the Cisco NX-OS configuration guide.</Description>
      </Remediation>
    </Remediations>
    <References>
      <Reference Type="Self">
        <URL>https://tools.cisco.com/security/center/content/CiscoSecurityAdvisory/cisco-sa-20181017-nxos-snmp</URL>
        <Description>Cisco NX-OS Software Authenticated Simple Network Management Protocol Denial of Service Vulnerability</Description>
      </Reference>
    </References>
  </Vulnerability>
</cvrf:cvrfdoc>